Yu-Jen Lai (Ian) 賴裕仁

Phone: +81-80-6528-0377

Mail: <u>ian.explore.world@gmail.com</u>
GitHub: <u>https://github.com/ianlai</u>

Summary

Self-motivated software engineer who can contribute comprehensive network and storage knowledge with handson programming skill. Trilingual, fluent in Mandarin, English and Japanese, who possesses 5-year software work experiences across Taiwan and Japan. Enjoy immersion in new web technology and seek a web-based engineering position engaged with network technology, e.g., backend engineer.

Skills

Programming: Java, Android, Python, C, C++, Shell Script, MATLAB, SQLite

• **Network:** Wi-Fi, TCP/IP, Wireshark, NS₂, EXata

System & Tools: AWS EC2, Heroku, Cloud9, OpenStack, Vagrant, VirtualBox, QEMU, Linux, Bash, Git, SVN

• Web - Frontend: HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript (ES₅, ES₆), jQuery

• Web - Backend: Node.js, Express, MongoDB, MySQL

• Language: Mandarin, English, Japanese (N1), Taiwanese

Working Experiences

Technical consultant

Flash Storage Strategy, Toshiba Memory Corporation

Tokyo, Japan

- New business development for NVMeoF storage software targeting in high performance IOs in data centers
- 2017.07 Present
- Coordinate cross-functional teams to identify potential system partners and customers, translate insight into product development and PoC evaluation, and receive customer buy-in.
- Establish the demo system, present it in exhibitions, educate the users its architecture, configuration and operation of the software for customer's PoC evaluation.

Software Research Engineer

Memory Research Center, Toshiba Memory Corporation

Yokohama, Japan 2013.11 - Present

Workload analysis for NVM (non-volatile memory) [1 yr]

- Built benchmark toolkits based on NVM Library (C-language); measured the performance in application layer, e.g. SQLite, MySQL, MongoDB, and the proprietary toolkit, with different IO access paths.
- Delved large-scale distributed systems' underlying mechanisms, e.g., GFS, BigTable, MapReduce, Spanner,
 HDFS, Ceph, etc.
- Multicast-Multihop-based Wi-Fi content sharing platform [2.5 yr]
 - Designed and implemented a platform for content sharing on both single board computer (ruby) and smart phone (android); conducted experiments in a 100-node large-scale testbed.
 - Identified and pitched to partners for joint R&D to scope out the economic model for commercialization.
 - Published 4 patents (pending) and an academic paper.

Software Engineer

Android Mobile, ASUS Computer Inc.

Taipei, Taiwan

• Designed, implemented, tested, debugged, ported features for Android's webkit-based stock browser

2012.11 - 2013.10

- Implemented the Most Visited feature and enhanced it's algorithm.
- Implemented a Chrome extension to access documents in Google Drive for syncing page with browser.
- · Designed, implemented, tested, debugged, ported features for wireless settings of Android
 - Took the responsibility solving the problems from all wireless functions including Wi-Fi, Bluetooth, Wi-Fi Direct and hotspot tethering in application layer (platforms: Qualcomm, MTK, Intel and NVIDIA).
 - Implemented a feature to let user block certain APs to avoid annoying messages.

Special Research Student

Asami & Kawahara Lab, The University of Tokyo

Tokyo, Japan

• Wireless communication protocols for high-speed trains (collaborating with Central Japan Railway)

2010.10 - 2011.09

 Conducted behavior analysis of TCP/UDP traffics, designed and implemented an emulator for reproducing a similar high-speed environment. Published 1 academic paper.

Research Assistant

Wireless Mobile Network Lab, National Taiwan University

Taipei, Taiwan

• Accelerometer-assisted adaptive 802.11 for public transportation system

2008.10 - 2010.09

 Led a project to design and implement a system utilizing train's acceleration info to enhance rate adaptation, conducted experiments on Taipei MRT to test the performance (1.6x throughput gain and 50% energy save). Published 2 academic papers.

Educations

M.S. in Electrical Engineering graduate institute, National Taiwan University (Wireless Mobile Network Lab)
 2008.09 - 2011.09

• Special Research Student in The University of Tokyo (Asami Kawahara Lab)

2010.09 - 2011.08

B.S. in Electrical Engineering, National Taiwan University

2004.09 - 2008.06

2011.03

Coding Side Projects

Project 1:	A pure frontend game (no network needed).	Frontend:	HTML, CSS, JavaScript
Color Guessing Game	The app gives a RGB value and let the user guess the corresponding color. The user receives the final score according to the remaining time and the correct ratio.	Deploy:	GitHub Pages
		URL:	https://ianlai.github.io/
		GitHub:	https://github.com/ianlai/ianlai.github.id
Project 2:	Server-side rendering website (Full-Stack).	Frontend:	HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap
Taiwan Spot	The website lets users register an account and then send a post to introduce a visiting spot. Other users can comment on the posts. The posts and comments can be edited or deleted by the user who owns them. The website supports responsive design, so different screen sizes can have their suitable views.	Backend:	Node.js, Express, MongoDB
		Deploy:	Heroku, mLab
		URL:	https://taiwanspots.herokuapp.com/
		GitHub:	https://github.com/ianlai/taiwan-spots
Project 3:	Client-side rendering single page app (Full-Stack).	Frontend:	HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, Ajax
Ajax Todo List	The user can add, toggle status, and delete a todo event in a single web page without reload. The server hosts the entry page and the Rest APIs. Once the entry page is loaded, the client sends Ajax request to the APIs to retrieve the data in	Backend:	Node.js, Express, MongoDB
		Deploy:	Heroku, mLab
		URL:	http://ajaxtodolist.herokuapp.com/
			* '
	the database and render the page with JSON response.	GitHub:	https://github.com/ianlai/ajax-todo-list
Project 4:	To keep polishing the skills of common algorithm and data	Language:	Java
Java Coding	structure with Java, I created a repository and wrote over 200	GitHub:	https://github.com/ianlai/Note-Java
	java examples which covers the topics including linked list,		
	tree, math, string, bit manipulation, sorting, dynamic		
	programming, backtracking, etc. Besides, it also contains		
	some experiment results, e.g., performance comparison		
	between different sorting schemes, performance comparison		
	between different sizes of the array in a hash map.		

Publications

mer	
1	mer

• Yu-Jen Lai, Wei-Hao Kuo, Wan-Ting Chiu, Hung-Yu Wei, "<u>Accelerometer-Assisted 802.11 Rate Adaptation on Mobile WiFi Access</u>", EURASIP Journal on Wireless Communications and Networking, August 2012

Kazuto Shimizu, **Yu-Jen Lai**, Kazuhiro Yamada, Yoshihiro Kawahara, and Tohru Asami, "<u>Design and Evaluation of an Emulator for High Speed Mobile Communication Environment Based on IEEE 802.11g</u>", Technical Report of IEICE (Japanese), March 2011

Yu-Jen Lai, Wei-Hao Kuo, Wan-Ting Chiu, Shao-Ting Chang, Hung-Yu Wei, "Accelerometer-Assisted 802.11 Rate
 Adaptation on Mass Rapid Transit System", ACM SIGCOMM (poster), August 2010